<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Way of the coder</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-03-31T08:55:30+02:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Gianluca Romanin</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>romaninz@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Middle Way]]></title>
  <link>/personal/the-way</link>
  <id>/personal/the-way</id>
  <published>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gianluca Romanin</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>romaninz@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a software engineer and crafting software is also my real passion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very lucky: I have a wonderful
family, a delightful wife, two beautiful daughters and I do what I like as an everyday job.
Not all of us have this kind of luck and I’m aware of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I forget about it and negative thoughts prevail.
This is the reason I decided to write this blog.
All you can find here, is not exactly what it is, but rather what it should be.
Writing is a big step into the road to improve myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are only two mistakes one can make along the road to truth; not going all the way, and not starting.
&lt;small&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Gautama Buddha&quot;&gt;Gautama Buddha&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in the real world is much more difficult than what a blog post can show.
There aren’t enough words to explain the complexity of working with a lot of people,
a lot of different personalities and quite different minds.
Tecnical stuff is pretty easy: learn, try, adopt, think, improve, restart.
Dealing with people is much more difficult and working in the world of connection and globalization is complex.
Every engineer is striken by a lot of tasks, issues, requests, time/resource constraints and conflicts.
Our mind is full of thoughts, all streaming at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all this, you have to look for harmony in your own home and family.
So in the end, a lot of us have some kind of shutdown.
Maybe your shutdown is a violent event or maybe is just a short period.
We need to put organization in our life to restart: be simple, be minimal, do less, do it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last year I read a nice book that helped me to open up my mind a little more.
The name of the book is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zenprogrammer.org/&quot;&gt;“Zen Programmer”&lt;/a&gt; by Christian Grobmeier
and it is a nice work that I really suggest to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fascinated by oriental phylosophies.
Buddhism and Confucianism theorized about the human
behaviour for centuries. They cover human issues to 360 degrees.
I had a wide path this year.
I discovered Hagakure and the Bushido. I read about samurai codes and values.
I read about chivalry code. I read about minimalism, decluttering, zen.
I found Leo Babauta’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/&quot;&gt;Zen Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put it all together. Returning on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am a software engineer and &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/care/&quot;&gt;I do care about my work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;small&gt;Me&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are used to have targets and missions.
However the target or the mission is not the end point of your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The road of life twists and turns and no two directions are ever the same.
Yet our lessons come from the journey, not the destination.
&lt;small&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Don Williams Jr.&quot;&gt;Don Williams Jr.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is the journey.
So we have to learn and work hard to improve ourself.
There are multiple colors in the world: not only black and not only white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is needed for us to see and appreciate all the nuances.&lt;br /&gt;
The middle way is the key.&lt;br /&gt;
Do not be strict. Do not be careless.&lt;br /&gt;
Do not be stubborn. Do not be submissive.&lt;br /&gt;
Look. Do not close your eyes to the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Listen. Do not allow your ego to prevail others.&lt;br /&gt;
Care.&lt;br /&gt;
This is the difference between crashing into things and beeing part of them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Me&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/personal/the-way&quot;&gt;The Middle Way&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Gianluca Romanin at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Way of the coder&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
